<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-06-24T13:21:38+03:00</updated><id>/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Rifat Cholakov - Personal Portfolio and Blog</title><subtitle>This is base description!!!</subtitle><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><entry><title type="html">Which A/B Testing Tool Should You Use?</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/27/first-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Which A/B Testing Tool Should You Use?" /><published>2018-11-27T01:56:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-27T01:56:00+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/27/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/27/first-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Which A/B Testing Tool Should You Use?&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Tuesday 27 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
        When visitors arrive on your company’s website, you want them to take action. Depending on your business, that “action” may be many different things, from filling out a contact form to making a purchase.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Regardless, you should improve your site to make converting as easy as possible for your visitors. The best way to do this is with conversion rate optimization.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One of the simplest ways to optimize a site is with A/B testing, or by creating two versions of the same element and showing them to real visitors to see which performs better. As you run these tests on different parts of your site, you’ll be able to optimize each page for a higher conversion rate.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before you get started, though, you’ll need to select a tool to help you set up, monitor, and review your tests. There are many available online, but the following four are our top picks at WebFX.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;1. Google Content Experiments&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cost: Free&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re just starting with A/B tests, Google Content Experiments are perfect for you. They’re entirely free to run and integrate directly with Google Analytics.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For a standard A/B test, you create two versions of a page, determine how long you want the test to run, and set a percentage of your site traffic to experiment with. However, if you have multiple versions of a page, the platform will allow you to test up to 10.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/google.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After your test has run for the set amount of time, you’ll be able to see which version got the most conversions and each page’s probability of outperforming the original one.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/google-results.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Based on this information, you can implement the winning page permanently.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;2. VWO&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cost: $49 – $999/month &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unlike Google Content Experiments, which require you to create your own pages, Visual Website Optimizer allows you to create variations of your pages within the platform using a WYSIWYG interface. After you copy and paste a “smart code” into the head of your website, there’s no HTML knowledge required.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can use simple drag-and-drop style tools to alter buttons, text, colors, photos, and other elements. Then, VWO will run the tests without altering the actual code on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can monitor your tests as often as you like to see which variations are performing best. You can also use additional tools like personalized content (based on a visitor’s location or device) and heatmap testing.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/vwo.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Although running tests with VWO does not require HTML knowledge, implementing the winning variation does. Once you’ve determine a winner, you’ll need to alter the original page manually.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s certainly easier to just let the VWO version run permanently, but stopping the test and changing the original page instead will prevent your site from experiencing any slow load times.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;3. Optimizely&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cost: Free – “Custom” &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Much like VWO, Optimizely allows you to run tests without altering your site manually. Instead, you can use the platform to create “overlays” of the original page. Just place their “snippet” in the head of your site, and you can run tests on any page.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/optimizely.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Optimizely’s tools make it easy to create and test different versions of your pages, and their free version offers everything you need to run basic A/B tests. They also create custom plans for professional users who want more features, like multi-page testing, visitor segmentation, and custom reports.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;4. Unbounce&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Cost: $49 – $199/month&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Although Unbounce is technically a landing page creation tool, it also allows users to run A/B tests. Because of this, it’s a good choice to optimize your landing pages.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can alter your calls to action, copy, images, and video on your page. If you have a contact form or other type of form, you can vary the number of fields, as well as the number of steps required to complete it.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once you’ve created your pages, you’ll see the results in the form of their conversion rates.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/unbounce.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the landing pages are for specific campaigns or offers, you may not even need to make the changes permanent on your site. Let Unbounce run the optimized page as long as you need, then simply remove it from your site when you no longer need it.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Which tool is right for you?&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All four of the tools above are great options for running A/B tests, but the one that’s best for your company depends on your needs.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re looking to run a simple test and have the HTML ability to create pages yourself, Google Content Experiments are all you need.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’d rather use an editor to cut down on time, Optimizely is a solid choice. And if you’re looking for advanced reporting tools or landing-page-specific features, you can’t go wrong with VWO or Unbounce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">Which A/B Testing Tool Should You Use? Tuesday 27 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov When visitors arrive on your company’s website, you want them to take action. Depending on your business, that “action” may be many different things, from filling out a contact form to making a purchase.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Build an Award-Winning Web Design Team</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/fifth-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Build an Award-Winning Web Design Team" /><published>2018-11-23T23:13:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T23:13:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/fifth-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/fifth-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h2&gt;How to Build an Award-Winning Web Design Team&lt;/h2&gt;
        &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Friday 23 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
                As Art Director over at Vintage, I have had the opportunity to build and grow an outstanding web design team. Together, our team has managed to work on plenty of innovative, award-winning projects. I would like to share some of my tips and techniques for hiring, helping cultivate the skills of team members, and creating a productive team culture.
        &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Hiring&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the web design industry, there is no shortage of potential employees. A highly-driven individual with a bit of talent, a computer, and Internet access has the capacity to learn the basics of web design. This low barrier to entry is a blessing and curse—as an employer, you have to put in a lot of time and hard work to find a gem in a pile of rhinestones.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To help choose and make sure potential team members are a good fit for our design team, I use these five principles: &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Start with a lot, end up with a few. The larger you initial pool of candidates, the better your chances are of getting at least one qualified candidate to the interview process. Don’t be afraid to screen out tens and even hundreds of resumes and work samples. Talented people are extremely rare, but they are out there. In my experience, out of about 100 people, only 2 to 3 end up being qualified. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Look for team members who want to work for you. A person who knows nothing about your design agency, or one who doesn’t value the mission and vision of your organization, is quite frankly not a good investment. A candidate who clearly recognizes they will be working for a great web agency will be more driven, happy, and motivated. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Don’t hire seniors and middles. For me, it’s worth the effort to find people with potential—a newly-minted designer who might not have the experience and skills yet, but who displays the willingness to grow and learn. This gives me the chance to direct that potential in my own watercourse. When you bring people up, they adjust easily to your style and vision. With accomplished designers, sometimes egos and stubborn habits get in the way of team cooperation. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; No country for the lone wolves! Every designer has to be focused on their inner-self to some extent, in order to give birth to new ideas. On the other hand, teamwork can’t happen without communication. If a person is not eager to chat, they will likely not integrate into the team well. If a person likes working alone, a better option for them would be to become a freelancer or to start their own agency. But in a large web production studio, you have to be a part of the team. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Leverage your social network. This technique is rather straightforward, yet it’s drastically underestimated: When it comes to hiring, take advantage of your network, both online and offline. People who follow you on social media, Dribbble, Behance, those who attend your lectures, people you have met in conferences, and so forth. One other thing I do is I encourage young designers to send me their work, and I give them a design critique for free. If the person is open to constructive feedback, and uses it as a tool to educate themselves and evolve as a designer, I know I will have a great candidate once I need to add a member to my team. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;h3&gt;Growth&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So, let’s say you have found and hired some people. Your job isn’t done, it has just begun. Here’s my advice for cultivating the skills of your team members and helping them flourish in their roles: &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Encourage continuous learning and improvement. This is going to sound harsh, but in my experience, a junior designer who stays at junior level for more than 6 months will probably never grow within the organization. A new employee must be able to improve their skills and work capacity, and be able to handle more than you require from them without external motivation. In other words, a junior designer must have a self-driven desire to learn and work hard. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Inspire excellence. I make it a rule for my team members to study the Awwwards daily ratings (Full disclosure: I’m a member of the Awwwards jury). When you regularly look at award-winning designs, you will have the opportunity to learn from other people’s successes. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Promote the idea that hard work drives success. A designer who is set to become more than they are, in my opinion, should never put salary at the forefront of their priorities. A designer who finds passion in creating things, making the world a nicer place to live in, who puts their soul into every creation, will achieve success in due course. Lust for money never pays off. On the other hand, if a person’s primary goal is to become the best at what they do, money will most certainly follow. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Give critiques regularly.Critique can be a tough pill to swallow for some. This is especially true for creative minds. Team members that see critique as a tool for self-improvement are the ones who take a step up the ladder. Conversely, the ones who fail to embrace constructive feedback often have a hard time advancing in their careers. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Be a mentor. Every budding designer needs a source of inspiration, a visionary who can guide their concepts until they are bold enough to produce their own. In every trade, mentors play a major role in the making of a successful professional. An effective leader must be a catalyst for creativity and innovation. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;h3&gt;Team Culture&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Eventually, you will be able to help junior designers become calibrated to the standards, culture, style, and other base requirements of your design team. But what will it take for you to help them progress towards producing masterwork-quality designs? &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Encourage a teamwork-friendly culture. A team is not just a group of people overseen by a person in a fancy chair. An effective team is one where everyone has each other’s backs. It’s crucial that team members don’t compete with each other but instead share their knowledge, blunders, and experience with the team. This way, they will never run short of inspiration sources, and will learn from each other’s achievements and mistakes. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Develop a workspace that’s favorable to creativity. Ideas and productivity depends a lot on a person’s emotional, intellectual, and physical well-being. A designer must be inspired by their surroundings. Therefore, it is important to accommodate them in a workplace that encourages creation. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Engage and encourage communication. Hold briefings, roundtables, and coffee breaks often. Discuss your projects. Create a culture wherein a team member isn’t afraid to share ideas and opinions, even if they contradict with yours. A team leader who values everyone’s contribution is an effective one. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Make the wheel turn by itself. When I hired my first three designers, I guided them personally through workflow, schedules, and procedures. But when I took in the fourth one, I left his accommodation to be handled by the previous three. This way of team organization further contributes to mutual understanding and partner attitude. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Show your team you care. The well-being of your designers will reflect upon your projects. A good leader never forgets that we are all human. No one benefits if a designer is too exhausted and burned out from being forced to work day and night, non-stop. Commitment, dedication, and hard work has to be rewarded, and it’s a good idea to give a team member who has recently went above and beyond the call of duty a less-burdening task or even a mini-vacation after a big project is successfully finish &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;

    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;My grandfather told me once that hard work makes a person. I never really believed that until I became an art director.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many people think that design is an innate ability, as if a person is born with (or without) a special gift that somehow automatically allows them to create world-class designs.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But looking back at my experience, I can undoubtedly say that even the most talented designers in the world would not be able to achieve their level of success without a strong desire to keep learning and improving, the hunger to be the best at what they do, and the diligence to put in the hard work. These are the concepts that must be championed in a design team.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you manage to build a team that has continuous self-improvement, excellence, and hard work as its foundation, there will truly be no project on this earth that’s impossible for you to do.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Principles of Building an Award-Winning Design Team&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Below is a visual of the tips and techniques discussed in this article. You may want to print this image for future reference. Click the image to enlarge it.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0594-01-principles-web-design-team.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;

&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">How to Build an Award-Winning Web Design Team Friday 23 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov As Art Director over at Vintage, I have had the opportunity to build and grow an outstanding web design team. Together, our team has managed to work on plenty of innovative, award-winning projects. I would like to share some of my tips and techniques for hiring, helping cultivate the skills of team members, and creating a productive team culture.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How Selling Pastries Helped Us Design a Better Product</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/fourth-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How Selling Pastries Helped Us Design a Better Product" /><published>2018-11-23T22:13:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T22:13:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/fourth-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/fourth-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;How Selling Pastries Helped Us Design a Better Product&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Friday 23 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
            It’s 8:30 in the morning and employees are trickling into the office kitchen, bleary-eyed and cocooned in thick scarves. Soft greetings are whispered over the tinkling of Cheerios.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What they don’t notice is Alan, one of our product managers, beaming from the center of an extravagant display of breakfast pastries.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0590-01-cookies.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“Get your bagels! Muffins! Croissants!” Alan shouts. Within seconds, people swarm the table.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Terry, a Scrum master, starts taking orders.  “How would you like to pay?” he asks.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In Terry’s hand is a prototype of our new card reader, connected to an iPhone. He swipes a credit card, hands the phone over for a quick signature, and relinquishes a pastry.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“How was your experience?” I ask the customer, once breakfast is safely in hand. “If you had to give this experience a rating between 1–7, what would you give it?”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For everyone else, it was time for breakfast. For my team, it was time to learn.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Released earlier this year, the FreshBooks Card Reader is a mobile point-of-sale device for freelancers and small business owners. It’s our team’s first ever physical product.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0590-02-freshbooks-card-reader.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For my product team, this uncharted territory presented some challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For example, typically, we would have direct access to our end-user, letting us test and get feedback at every stage of the design, and to better understand their needs and goals. But, because the product was in stealth mode, we weren’t yet openly sharing it outside of our Toronto office.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The lengthy hardware production cycle also meant we often didn’t have a card reader in our hands for much of the design process.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So, without access to either the end-user or hardware, how were we to uncover the insights we needed to create an exceptional user experience?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The solution, it turns out, was not to simply test our prototypes with our own employees. Instead, we recreated not only the scenario, but also an environment in which a card reader transaction might take place, in order to better understand the real-world implications of our design.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So we built a café in our kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The kitchen café proved to be both delicious and informative. Below are a few ways this experiment helped us design a better product.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We were able to see the real-world dynamics between people.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We knew that the experience had to be simple and usable from both the merchant’s and customer’s perspective. The problem was that we weren’t sure exactly what “simple and usable” meant in this context (because it’s uncharted territory for us), and how that interaction would feel.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These were the types of questions we wanted to answer through the café experiment: &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; How would the merchant react when the device failed to respond to the swipe of a card? What would he/she say, and how awkward would the situation be? &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; What questions might the customer ask the merchant regarding the device failure? Would the customer feel it was their fault the card-swipe failed? &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; And, most importantly, what could we do (design-wise) to avoid these concerns? &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By the end of the morning, we had observed dozens of simulated transactions and closed up shop with a much better understanding of our product’s role in the merchant/customer interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It revealed emotions and usability issues that arise in stressful situations.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At 8:45 a.m. the café was fairly quiet. But 15 minutes later, the floodgates had opened and business was booming.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Observing an experience in a quiet, controlled environment can be helpful. But apply just a wee bit of chaos and you can unlock insights into real-world behaviors and emotions. This gave us insight into how a merchant could be affected by external factors and stress. Would they rush through the transaction? Would the customer feel the pressure and swipe their card the wrong way, ignoring our on-screen instructions?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We were able to better consider the interplay between hardware and software.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While we were able to test the software easily enough, we were still missing one important part: The card reader itself.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0590-03-freshbooks-card-reader-mockup.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For most of the product development cycle, we had no stand-in for the final product in our scenarios. How would we confidently grade the experience when we were missing such a key component?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Well, we recreated that too. Although we didn’t have the device, we had the specs and we promptly sent them off to a local 3D printer who spooled out a replica of the card reader within a day. A coat of paint and a few stickers later, and we had something that looked and felt pretty close to the real thing.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We were able to use this crude replica to gauge how the device would sit in the customer’s hand, how easy it was to swipe or insert a credit card, and the emotional reaction to the overall design including branding and color.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It helped us focus our efforts when it came time to test and monitor the product with real users.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It should go without saying that testing our product internally did not — and could not — completely replace testing with our end-users. Even though our Toronto employees provided us with plenty of lessons and served well as temporary stand-ins for real users during our café experiment, they were not our actual customers.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Although we were able to draw out many valuable insights by recreating real-world scenarios, nothing could be answered conclusively. The most we could ask for was the emergence of new questions, a little more empathy, and indicators of what should be rigorously tested and monitored in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Therefore it was essential that we understood what exactly we wanted to learn before we tested anything internally. The types of questions that we asked, and the kinds of behavior we wanted to observe, were influenced by the understanding that we were watching fiction.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;hr&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By the end of the morning, once the dust had settled, we had sold everything but a lone cream cheese bagel and a plain croissant.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Although we were tired and frazzled, we were also very happy. By conducting a simple, short experiment, we had learned things we could have only previously speculated.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The proof was in my hands — a clipboard bursting with valuable feedback and observations.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As we walked back to our desks amidst the clamor of a routine Monday morning, our conversation was buzzing with new insights, new questions, and new problems to solve.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While we still had a long way to go, recreating real-life scenarios proved to be an invaluable way to start challenging our assumptions and build empathy for our customers in a short amount of time.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And we didn’t even have to leave our office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">How Selling Pastries Helped Us Design a Better Product Friday 23 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov It’s 8:30 in the morning and employees are trickling into the office kitchen, bleary-eyed and cocooned in thick scarves. Soft greetings are whispered over the tinkling of Cheerios.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Speed Up Your Website With CDN77</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/third-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speed Up Your Website With CDN77" /><published>2018-11-23T21:13:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T21:13:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/third-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/third-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Speed Up Your Website With CDN77&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Friday 23 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
        Want to make your website faster? Using a content delivery network (CDN) will bring remarkable speed improvements to your website.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CDN77 is an excellent content delivery network. They’re a customer-centric, performance-focused company that continually enhances their service through the rapid and early adoption of cutting-edge features.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For example, right now, not a lot of CDNs support Brotli — a Google-led compression format that reduces file sizes 22% better than gzip. CDN77 recently implemented Brotli compression support, which means faster file transfers for users on their CDN.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Why CDN77?&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/cdn.designinstruct.com/files/640-cdn77-review/03-cdn77-homepage.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CDN77 offers you a ton of features at a cost-effective price point. That’s probably one of the biggest reasons why over 19,500 websites rely on them.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I’ll talk about the top 5 things I like most about CDN77.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;User-friendly design&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CDN77?s control panel is super intuitive, so analyzing your traffic stats and performance reports, and managing your account is a breeze with their user interface.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/cdn.designinstruct.com/files/640-cdn77-review/04-cdn77-control-panel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Easy integration with WordPress and other content publishing platforms&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Using CDN77 can be as easy as installing a plugin. If you’re on WordPress, you have several plugin options such as W3 Total Cache, ZenCache, etc. Learn more here.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Better speeds because of HTTP/2 support&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The newest version of the Web’s standard data-transfer protocol, HTTP/2, is already enabled on CDN77. HTTP/2, according to my test results on http2demo.io, is 63% faster than HTTP.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/cdn.designinstruct.com/files/640-cdn77-review/05-http2demo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Free HTTPS support&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You might already know that HTTPS on your website is important for SEO because Google uses HTTPS as a ranking signal. CDN77 will serve your content using HTTPS at no extra cost.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Pay only for what you use&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CDN77 doesn’t have fixed monthly fees and hidden charges. You only pay for what you actually use. This means the cost scales proportionally to the traffic of your website.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Head over to CDN77 to learn more about this excellent content delivery network.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Try CDN77 for Free!&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;CDN77 gives you the opportunity to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cdn77.com/signup&quot;&gt;try them for free&lt;/a&gt;. No strings attached — no commitments, and no credit card required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">Speed Up Your Website With CDN77 Friday 23 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov Want to make your website faster? Using a content delivery network (CDN) will bring remarkable speed improvements to your website.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The 5 Best Free FTP Clients</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/second-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The 5 Best Free FTP Clients" /><published>2018-11-23T20:13:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T20:13:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/second-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/second-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;The 5 Best Free FTP Clients&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Friday 23 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
            Transferring files to and from your web host or server is best done with what’s commonly known an FTP client, though the term is a bit dated because there are more secure alternatives such as SFTP and FTPS.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When I was putting together this list, this was my criteria: &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Supports secure file transfer protocols: FTP isn’t secure. Among its many flaws, plain FTP doesn’t encrypt the data you’re transferring. If your data is compromised en route to its destination, your credentials (username and password) and your data can easily be read. SFTP (which stands for SHH File Transfer Protocol) is a popular secure alternative, but there are many others. &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Has a GUI: There are some awesome FTP clients with a command-line interface, but for a great number of people, a graphical user interface is more approachable and easier to use. &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://filezilla-project.org/&quot;&gt;1. FileZilla&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Topping the list is FileZilla, an open source FTP client. It’s fast, being able to handle simultaneous transmissions (multi-threaded transfers), and supports SFTP and FTPS (which stands for FTP over SSL). What’s more, it’s available on all operating systems, so if you work on multiple computers — like if you’re forced to use Windows at work but you have a Mac at home — you don’t need to use a different application for your file-transferring needs.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0585-01-filezilla.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Available on Windows, Mac OS and Linux&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cyberduck.io/&quot;&gt;2. Cyberduck&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cyberduck can take care of a ton of your file-transferring needs: SFTP, WebDav, Amazon S3, and more. It has a minimalist UI, which makes it super easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0585-02-cyberduck.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Available on Windows and Mac OS&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://fireftp.net/&quot;&gt;3. FireFTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This Mozilla Firefox add-on gives you a very capable FTP/SFTP client right within your browser. It’s available on all platforms that can run Firefox.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0585-03-fireftp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Available on Windows, Mac OS and Linux&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nchsoftware.com/classic/&quot;&gt;4. Classic FTP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Classic FTP is a file transfer client that’s free for non-commercial use. It has a very simple interface, which is a good thing, because it makes it easy and intuitive to use. I like its “Compare Directories” feature that’s helpful for seeing differences between your local and remote files.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0585-04-classic-ftp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Available on Windows and Mac OS&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://winscp.net/eng/index.php&quot;&gt;5. WinSCP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This popular FTP client has a very long list of features, and if you’re a Windows user, it’s certainly worth a look. WinSCP can deal with multiple file-transfer protocols (SFTP, SCP, FTP, and WebDav). It has a built-in text editor for making quick text edits more convenient, and has scripting support for power users.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0585-05-winscp.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Available on Windows&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Honorable Mention: &lt;a href=&quot;https://panic.com/transmit/&quot;&gt;Transmit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;For this post, I decided to focus on free software. But it just doesn’t seem right to leave out Transmit (which costs $34) in a post about FTP clients because it’s a popular option used by web developers on Mac OS. It has a lot of innovative features and its user-friendliness is unmatched. If you’ve got the cash to spare and you’re on a Mac, this might be your best option.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/images/assets/cdn.sixrevisions.com/0585-06-transmit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Available on Mac OS&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">The 5 Best Free FTP Clients Friday 23 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov Transferring files to and from your web host or server is best done with what’s commonly known an FTP client, though the term is a bit dated because there are more secure alternatives such as SFTP and FTPS.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Fix (and Avoid) Traffic Drops after a Website Redesign</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/sixth-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Fix (and Avoid) Traffic Drops after a Website Redesign" /><published>2018-11-23T15:13:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T15:13:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/sixth-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/sixth-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;How to Fix (and Avoid) Traffic Drops after a Website Redesign&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Friday 23 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
        No matter how state-of-the-art your company’s website may have seemed when you first launched it, there comes a time when every site can benefit from a redesign. Given the multitude of algorithm changes than happen each year, and regular shifts in consumer Internet use, it can be nearly impossible for an outdated website to deliver the online results you need.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’ve recently launched a redesign, you were likely excited to see the results of your revamped site, like increases in traffic, conversions, and sales. And when done right, this is exactly what happens.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it isn’t always the case – in fact, some site owners actually lose site traffic in the days and weeks following their website redesign.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re currently experiencing this issue, keep reading for 3 possible reasons, as well as how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And if you’re considering redesigning your site in the future, we’ve also included 5 tips for avoiding traffic drops altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Causes for traffic drops after a redesign&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, it’s important to note that minor traffic drops are completely normal for a few days following a redesign. If it’s been less than a week, and the decline is less than 10%, you may have nothing to worry about.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Google needs to crawl and index all of your new pages in order to serve the new versions to their users, so you should expect a temporary decline in organic traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;That being said, if it’s been more than a few days, or traffic has dropped off drastically, there’s likely a bigger issue at play. And if that’s the case, you’ll want to inspect the following three elements.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;1. Redirects&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;One of the most important steps in a website redesign is setting up proper redirects – and skipping this step is one of the most common causes of traffic loss.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Unless you keep all of your URLs exactly the same (and recreate each of your old pages on your new site), redirects are absolutely necessary. They tell search engines and browsers where the new version of each page is located – and without them, they’ll simply think the page is gone.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you changed your URL structure or moved any pages to new locations, but didn’t set up proper redirects, this is likely the main cause of your traffic drop.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;And if you’re not sure if this is the issue, you can log into Google’s Search Console, then go to Crawl &gt; Crawl Errors and select the “Not Found” tab.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/img/not-found.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If there are any pages without redirects on your site, they’ll show up here.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In order to fix the issue – and regain your traffic – you’ll need to implement 301 redirects for each of your old pages. Then, if you don’t have any other issues, your traffic levels should be back to normal within a few weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;2. Site structure&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your site structure plays an important role in how Google indexes and understands your site, so if it drastically changed during your redesign, you’ll need to create a new sitemap.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Your sitemap provides a basic listing of all of the important pages on your site, and you can submit it to Search Console to speed up the process of re-indexing your pages and restoring your traffic levels.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In addition to your sitemap, you’ll also want to revisit your internal links. The links within your pages (especially your navigation) play an important role in how Google indexes your site. If some – or all – of these point to outdated URLs, this could also cause crawl issues.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;3. Site copy&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In some cases, website redesigns also involve entirely new copy. And while this can be helpful if the copywriter was aware of and incorporated the original target keywords, it can be extremely detrimental if not.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your pages are no longer written in a way that includes the keywords they originally ranked for, your rankings will suffer for those keywords. Google’s algorithm is designed to provide their users with the information they’re looking for – and if your site no longer has that information, they won’t show it as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The best way to fix this issue is to work with an experienced SEO who can optimize your pages for your target keywords. And if you have a backup of your old site saved somewhere, you can use it to determine which keywords to use on each page.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;How long it takes for traffic to return to normal levels&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your traffic dropped as a result of one of the issues above, you should make it a top priority to remedy the problem as soon as possible. That being said, your traffic likely won’t come back overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It may take a few weeks for Google to crawl and re-index all of your new pages, and until they begin ranking in search results again, your traffic will be lower that usual.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;How to avoid traffic drops during a redesign&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you haven’t yet redesigned your site, the information above may have you second-guessing whether it’s really worth it. But if your site is outdated, a redesign can certainly have a positive impact – you just need to be sure to take the following steps:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;1. Make SEO part of the process&lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure that your redesign team regularly consults an SEO strategist throughout the process. Although your design agency may have experts in design and development, the perspective of an experienced SEO will help you avoid serious issues that result in traffic loss.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They may also be able to advise changes that will help your traffic levels improve after the redesign, and make the process even more worthwhile for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;2. Crawl your existing site and plan your new site architecture&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before making any changes, you should first take an inventory of every page currently on your site. There are many free tools online that will help you do this and provide your results in a downloadable spreadsheet.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This will help you make sure that all of the valuable information currently on your site has a place on the redesigned version, and you can also use it to build out a new site architecture, if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In some cases, your URLs and general structure can remain the same. But if your current URLs aren’t set up in a logical way (ex. With relevant subfolders and appropriate page titles), a redesign is the perfect opportunity to fix this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;3. Set up 301 redirects&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As we mentioned above, not having proper redirects in place is the most common cause for traffic loss. If your URLs have changed at all, you’ll need to set them up before launching your new site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You should also make sure that each one is set up as a 301 (permanent) redirect, as this tells search engine crawlers that the page has permanently moved. Using 302 (temporary) redirects is a common error, but one that can harm your rankings.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;4. Create a new sitemap&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Before launching your site, you should also create a new sitemap that includes all of the most important pages on your site. As a general rule of thumb, you shouldn’t include more than 100 pages – so if your site is huge, your sitemap may be more of a general overview than a comprehensive listing.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;5. Make sure your analytics tracking code is in place&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finally, before your launch, double check that your analytics tracking code is in place on your new site. Although this may seem like a no-brainer, it’s a common oversight – and one that can lead you to believe that you’ve lost all of your traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Simply making sure that the code is implemented in your header or footer can save you that stress, and will also allow you to monitor your traffic during every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">How to Fix (and Avoid) Traffic Drops after a Website Redesign Friday 23 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov No matter how state-of-the-art your company’s website may have seemed when you first launched it, there comes a time when every site can benefit from a redesign. Given the multitude of algorithm changes than happen each year, and regular shifts in consumer Internet use, it can be nearly impossible for an outdated website to deliver the online results you need.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">5 Ways Web Design Impacts Customer Experience</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/seventh-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="5 Ways Web Design Impacts Customer Experience" /><published>2018-11-23T14:13:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T14:13:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/seventh-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/seventh-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;5 Ways Web Design Impacts Customer Experience&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Friday 23 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
        Web design is one of the most important parts of any Internet marketing strategy. It has a huge impact on the digital customer experience in several different ways. Your site’s aesthetics, usability, any other crucial factors are essential to your company’s long-term online success.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But how dramatically does it actually impact your bottom line?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In this post, we’ll take a look at five major aspect of web design and how you can improve all of them.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;1. Appearance&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/amazon-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Web design most obviously impacts your site’s appearance. You choose how your site looks, which plays a huge role in your company’s first impression on new online visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Often, you’ll hear marketing experts (including us) talk about web design in two extremes: &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Older websites that look like they were made in 1996 &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Newer, sleeker websites that adhere to modern web design standards
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Many websites fall between those two options, but they represent opposite ends of a spectrum.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It’s possible to have a site somewhere in the middle — one that looks attractive, but maybe it was last updated in 2007.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Regardless of how your site looks, the goal is to have it as current and up-to-date with modern design trends as you can.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Modern web design trends include: &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Responsive design &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Parallax scrolling &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Big, bold fonts &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Eye-catching “hero” images &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Multimedia &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Responsive design means using code on your website that makes it look and function the same, regardless of the device someone uses to access it.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So whether someone comes to your site from a smartphone or a desktop computer, they’ll get a great experience and find the information they want.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Parallax scrolling means overlaying two visual elements on a page and moving them at different speeds as someone scrolls.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then, when someone looks through a page on your site, they’ll get a cutting-edge visual experience that keeps them engaged and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Big, bold fonts have been in vogue for a few years now. Essentially, the concept refers to using sans-serif typefaces that are easy to read on screens.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;That makes your customer experience smoother, and it lets your readers get the most value out of every sentence on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Eye-catching “hero” images are giant, full-width graphics at the top of articles that give you a summarizing visual representation of the text below.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;They got the name “hero” because these images champion the article with which they’re associated. They’re great for generating clicks for social media, and they’re ideal introductions to concepts on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Last, multimedia refers to images, videos, interactives, and other visual elements that help break up text and educate your visitors.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Multimedia is fair game for just about any page on your site from a blog post to a 100-page downloadable guide.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When you include it, you make your content much more scannable, engaging, and enjoyable for readers.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;But this all has to do with your site’s appearance. Web design impacts a lot more than just how a website looks.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;2. Professionalism&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/testimonials-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Professionalism refers to the impression you make on your site’s visitors before they ever start reading your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When someone arrives on your site, you want them to understand that you’re a modern, respectable business. This impression is largely based on how your web design represents you.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Several web design elements contribute to professionalism, including: &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; A culture page &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Photos of staff &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Customer results &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A culture page is part of your site that’s exclusively dedicated to talking about your company’s approach to daily operations.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do you have certain values at your company? Do you maintain certain traditions? Do you celebrate anything unique?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These are all great additions to a culture page since they show what your company does besides work. Even your customers will be interested to see that your employees are happy.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Speaking of employee happiness, photos of staff can also go a long way in reinforcing professionalism.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whether you choose to show them together at a happy hour or hard at work is up to you. Either way, you’re adding faces to your business that shows visitors you’re more than a brand name — you’re a thriving company.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Last, you can showcase customer results. If you can quantify your work in any way — even if it’s how many air conditioners you repaired last year — you can highlight that information on your site.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This demonstrates professionalism because it shows that you have your customers in mind, even those who haven’t converted yet.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Visitors who see that will understand that you’re a customer-focused business that values itself in terms of what you can deliver.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Still, professionalism needs another element that web design can offer — and it’s essential no matter what kind of business you own.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;3. Clarity&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/groupon.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Clarity means designing your website so visitors can find what they want as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Most often, this means improving your navigation. Intuitive and familiar navigation styles allow your visitors to quickly find the information they want.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Today, navigation comes in a few well-known styles: &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Breadcrumb &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Drop-down menu &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Breadcrumb navigation is inspired by the story of Hansel &amp; Gretel.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whenever someone clicks to a new page, your site automatically adds their previous page to a navigation bar. Then, a user can click back to that page in an instant if they want.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A drop-down menu lets someone hover their cursor over a menu title and see the pages that category contains.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Then, they can click on the page that interests them to get the information they want.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;These navigation strategies can work together, too. Your homepage can use drop-down menus, and once someone clicks to a new page, you can use breadcrumb navigation on that page to let users go back to where they were.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Naturally, you have lots of other options for navigation. But these are the two most popular and useful in the web design world.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;4. Load time&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/web-design-ux-load-time.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Load time refers to how long someone has to wait for a page on your site to display on their device(s).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Load time is a major Google ranking factor, and it’s become crucial to online success as more consumers move toward using the Internet on mobile devices.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The modern Internet user is concerned with websites that load in the blink of an eye and — more importantly — use minimal data.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So how can you reduce your site’s loading time? &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Optimize image sizes &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Remove auto-play multimedia &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Use white space &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, you can optimize image sizes on your website to make sure your site loads as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To do that, use .jpg files for your images. This is the best way to show high-resolution photos or graphics while minimizing the size of the file.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Next, you should remove auto-play multimedia like video and audio.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;That means your users won’t use big chunks of their mobile data when they go to your site on their smartphones.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Plus, auto-play multimedia is an irritating way to promote content anyway. Most users will leave your page if they get there and there’s automatically a video in their face.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Instead, make your multimedia require manual activation on every page.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Last, you can use white space more frequently to reduce data demand.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;White space is any unused space on your pages. No text, no images, no videos — nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;White space spreads out your text and elements to make them easier to see, especially for mobile users.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This makes it easier for visitors to understand everything on a page so they don’t have to re-read content.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In a nutshell, that makes white space work on two levels. It helps your pages load in a flash and it makes them more readable.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Overall, that makes web design crucial to the speed of your site. You can also use these strategies together to help your individual pages load as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;5. Conversions&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/spotify.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Conversions are arguably the most important part of web design.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After all, your business won’t thrive online without them.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Web design can impact conversions in a thousand different ways, and they’re all important, but these three are some of the most impactful: &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Color &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; KISS principle &lt;br&gt;
        &amp;bull; Faces &lt;br&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Color sounds general, but in web design, it refers to a color scheme that intelligently uses contrast to highlight selling propositions.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So if your site uses a cool color scheme, use warm colors like red or yellow for your calls to action. That helps them stand out so people can find them more easily and convert.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The KISS principle is an acronym for “Keep It Simple, Stupid.”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The idea is that simpler designs are better designs. When you have an easy-to-follow, organized website, you make it that much easier for visitors to convert.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You don’t need loud backgrounds or showy graphics to sell your company online — it’s actually better to stay simple.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Last, faces may sound a little odd as a web design principle. But the idea is that human faces help visitors relate to your business.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You could use stock images, but this works best when you use your own staff.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Essentially, you show someone the human side of your company to make them feel more comfortable contacting you.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;It may not sound like much, but that goes a long way in establishing trust, fostering a positive relationship, and eventually earning a new customer.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By using all three of these concepts at once, you make your site much more efficient at earning new customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">5 Ways Web Design Impacts Customer Experience Friday 23 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov Web design is one of the most important parts of any Internet marketing strategy. It has a huge impact on the digital customer experience in several different ways. Your site’s aesthetics, usability, any other crucial factors are essential to your company’s long-term online success.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">How to Choose a Navigation Setup</title><link href="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/eigth-post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Choose a Navigation Setup" /><published>2018-11-23T13:13:20+02:00</published><updated>2018-11-23T13:13:20+02:00</updated><id>/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/eigth-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="/jekyll/update/2018/11/23/eigth-post.html">&lt;p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/Freelancer-Portfolio-and-Blogimages/post-8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Post Image&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;How to Choose a Navigation Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;meta-info&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;date&quot;&gt;Friday 23 November 2018 by &lt;span class=&quot;author&quot;&gt;Rifat Cholakov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p class=&quot;post-summary&quot;&gt;
        Do you want users to spend time on your site and stick around long enough to convert? If so, it’s essential that your content is easy to navigate. If finding information is difficult, users will likely become frustrated and leave, in search of a site that provides a better user experience.
    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;article&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A website that is easy to navigate will lead to longer visits and increased conversions. And given that your website’s ultimate goal is to generate sales and leads for your business, this is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are a few different ways to setup your site’s navigation, and two of the most popular are top and side. The one that’s best for your site depends on your content, so in this post, we’ll take a look at a few different navigation options and why they may or may not work for your business.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Top Navigation&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Top navigation may be the best setup for your site if you don’t have too many menu options to choose from. Most users are inclined to read left to right, top to bottom. Place the navigation labels in a horizontal line at the top of the page to create a familiar and natural space for users’ eyes to land.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ll want “top-level” pages, or pages that are the most important to your site, in this navigation bar.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Side Navigation&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vertical menus are usually not the best option if you’re aiming for simple menu design, because a lot of content can visually crowd vertical menus.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Looking at the example below from Yale University’s School of Art page, you can see how side navigation works:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/tisch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Compare this setup to the Tisch School of Art’s page:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/tisch.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Which one is easier on the eye and encourages further reading?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At first glance, it is easy to see that the Tisch School of Art makes it much easier to navigate their site and find important information. The top navigation setup is minimalist and elegant in design, with clear and concise labels.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;By contrast, Yale’s page has a more cluttered side navigation that, although simple, is less visually appealing.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Vertical navigation menus can work, but only with the right design and with minimal items to choose from.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Here’s an example where side navigation works well:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/nathan-welton.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As you can see, Nathan Welton Photography uses a minimalist design with few menu options. The result is a well-designed, easy-to-navigate homepage.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If your site features long lists of menu items, and you wish to use vertical navigation, be sure to break the menus into categories.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;However, if your site is content-heavy with lots of categories and information, you may want to opt for a mega nav setup.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Mega Navigation&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you have a lot of information on your site, a mega navigation setup is one of the best ways to make it all accessible to your visitors. It’s visually appealing, and entices users with plenty of organized options. If you offer many different products in different categories, this is likely your best option.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A great example of an easy-to-navigate drop-down menu can be found on Starbucks website.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/starbucks-nav.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When users hover their mouse over the “Menu” tab, they see a larger navigation setup with four different categories – all in a simple font, and neatly spaced. The point is to direct users where they want to go, not overwhelm them with unnecessary effects or images.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://www.webfx.com/blog/wp-content/uploads/2017/09/starbucks-nav-dropdown.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A mega drop-down menu will also add plenty of links to your site and will help with SEO as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Whether you choose top, side, or a mega navigation setup, you’ll want to make sure that the style is consistent on all pages, visually familiar, and concise.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be descriptive and specific in your navigation labels and put yourself in user’s shoes. Ask yourself what experience you prefer to have when browsing an online store for products or services. What have you found to be frustrating when navigating a page, and what changes would you have made?&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A navigation setup should be designed with the goal of getting users where they want to be as easily as possible. And when you make user experience your top priority, you’ll be much more successful in keeping visitors on your site and converting them into customers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/article&gt;</content><author><name>Rifat Cholakov</name></author><summary type="html">How to Choose a Navigation Setup Friday 23 November 2018 by Rifat Cholakov Do you want users to spend time on your site and stick around long enough to convert? If so, it’s essential that your content is easy to navigate. If finding information is difficult, users will likely become frustrated and leave, in search of a site that provides a better user experience.</summary></entry></feed>